In this video, I'm going to describe some relatively simple models of neurons.
在这个视频中 我将介绍一些相对简单的神经元模型
I'll describe a number of different models starting with simple linear and threshold
我将介绍几种不同的模型 首先是简单的线性阈值神经元
neurons, and then, describing slightly more complicated models.
然后还会介绍一些稍显复杂的模型
These are much simpler than real neurons, but they're still complicated enough, to
虽然这些模型比真正的神经元简单得多 但它们仍然具有足够的复杂性
allow us to make neural nets, that do some very interesting kinds of machine
足以允许我们用来构成神经网络 开展一些有趣的机器学习
learning. In order to understand anything
为了理解一个复杂的东西
complicated, we have to idealize it. That is, we have to make simplifications
我们必须对其进行理想化 即做一些简化
that allow us to get a handle on how it might work.
使得我们能够初步理解它是如何工作的
With atoms, for example, we simplify them as behaving like little solar systems.
打个比方 我们把原子内部运行简化成微小的太阳系
Idealization removes the complicated details that are not essential for
理想化的过程去除了那些对于理解主要规律 并不关键的复杂细节
understanding the main principles. It allows us to apply mathematics, and to
这使得我们能够对其进行数学处理
make analogies to other familiar systems. And once we understand the basic
并与其他相似系统进行类比 一旦我们理解了基本原理
principles, it's easy to add complexity, and make the model more faithful to
就可以增加模型的复杂性 让它能更好地还原现实
reality. Of course, we have to be careful when we
当然 在理想化的过程中 我们要特别小心
idealize something, not to remove the thing that's giving it its main
不能简化掉那关系到主要性质的东西
properties. It's often worth understanding models that
去了解那些已经被认为是错误的模型
are known to be wrong, as long as we don't forget they're wrong.
常常是值得的 只要我们别忘了它是错的
So for example, a lot of work on neural networks uses neurons that communicate
比如说 很多神经网络的研究使用的神经元 相互传递的是实值
real values rather than discrete spikes of activity, and we know cortical neurons
而不是离散的活动峰值 我们知道真正的脑细胞并不是这样工作的
don't behave like that, but it's still worth understanding systems like that, and
但这些系统依然值得我们去理解
in practice they can be very useful for machine learning.
在机器学习中他们其实是非常有用的
The first kind of neuron I want to tell you about is the simplest, it's a linear
我要介绍的第一种神经元是最简单的线性神经元
neuron. It's simple.
它很简单
It's computationally limited in what it can do.
它所能做的在计算上有所限制
It may allow us to get insights into more complicated neurons.
它能让我们深入探究更复杂的神经元
But it may be somewhat misleading. So in a linear neuron, the output Y.
但它也可能会有一点误导倾向 回到正题 在一个线性神经元中 输出Y
Is a function of a bi-asset in your run B and the sum of all its incoming
是这个神经元的偏置 (bias) b 以及
connections of the activity on an input line times the weight on that line that's
所有的输入连接与其对应的突触权值的乘积 的函数
the synaptic weight on the input line and if you plot that as curve, then if you
如果将它画出来
plot on the X-axis, the buyers plus the weighted activities on the input line we
X轴是偏置加上加权和
get a straight line that goes through zero.
将会得到一条过原点的直线
Very different from linear neurons, are binary threshold neurons that were
和线性神经有很大不同的 是阈值型神经元
introduced by McCulloch and Pitts. They actually influenced Von Roenam when
这个模型由麦卡洛克和皮兹发明 他们实际上在冯诺依曼思考如何设计通用计算机时
he was thinking about how to design a universal computer.
对其造成了不少影响
In a binary threshold neuron you first compute a weighted sum of the inputs and
在阈值型神经元中 你首先计算输入信号的加权和
then you send out a spike of activity if that weighted sum exceeds the threshold.
如果加权和超过了阈值 则发出一个峰值信号
[inaudible] and Pitts thought that the spikes were like the truth values of
麦卡洛克和皮兹认为 这些峰值就像是一系列命题的真值
propositions. So each neuron is combining the truth
每个神经元
values it gets from other neurons to produce the truth value of its own.
通过组合它从其他神经元得到的真值 来产生它自己的真值
And that's like combining some propositions to compute the truth value of
这就像组合一些命题 来计算另外一个命题的真值
another proposition. At the time in the 1940's logic was the
在1940年代 逻辑被认为是大脑工作的主要模式
main paradigm for how the mind might work. Since then people thinking about how the
从那时起 那些在思考大脑如何工作的人
brain computes have become much more interested in the idea the brain is
将兴趣更多地转移到了
combining lots of different sources of unreliable evidence.
大脑是如何组合大量不同来源的不可靠的数据
And so logic isn't such a good pardigm for what the brain's up to.
所以逻辑并不是决定大脑如何运行的一个好的模式
For a binary threshold neuron, you can think of its input/output function as if
对于一个阈值型神经元来说 你可以把它的输入输出函数
the weighted input is above the threshold, it gives an output of one.
看做决定于加权和是否高于阈值 如果是的话 则输出为1
Otherwise, it gives an output of zero. There are actually two equivalent ways to
否则 输出为0 实际上有两种等价的方式
write the equations for a binary threshold neuron.
来给出阈值型神经元的激活方程
We can say that the total input Z is just the activities on the input lines times
我们可以说 总的输入z 就是各输入信号乘上对应的权重 之和
the weights. And then the output Y is one if that Z is
如果z 大于阈值 则输出Y为1
above the threshold and zero otherwise. Alternatively, we could say that the total
否则为0 或者我们也可以说
input includes a bias term. So the total input is what comes in on the
输入还包含了一个偏置量 所以总的输入就等于
input lines, times the weights, plus this bias term.
各输入信号乘上对应权重 之和 再加上一个偏置量
And then we could say the output is one if that total input is above zero and is zero
然后如果 总输入大于0 则输出为1
otherwise. And the equivalence is simply that the
否则 输出为0 等价性是显而易见的
threshold in first formulation is equal to the negative of the bias in the second
第一个方程中的阈值 就等于第二个方程中的偏置量的负值
formulation. A kind of neuron that combines the
一种结合了
properties of both linear neurons and binary threshold neurons is a rectified
线性和阈值型神经元性质的神经元 就是分段线性神经元
linear neuron. It first computes a linear weighted sum of
它首先计算所有输入的权重和
its inputs, but then it gives an output that's a non-linear function of this
但是它的输出并不是这个权重和的线性函数
weighted sum. So we compute Z in the same way as before.
即我们按照之前的方法计算权重和 z
If z is below zero, we give an output of zero.
如果 z 小于0 则输出为0
Otherwise, we give an output that's equal to z.
否则 输出为z
So above zero is linear, and at zero, it makes a hard decision.
可以看到 z大于0的部分是线性的 而等于0时 则是不连续的
So the input/output curve looks like this. It's definitely not linear, but above zero
所以输入输出的曲线看起来是这样的 它显然不是线性的 但对大于0的部分
it is linear. So with a neuron like this, we can get a
它却是线性的 使用这样一个神经元
lot of the nice properties of linear systems, when it's above zero.
我们能在大于0的部分 得到线性系统的很多优良性质
We can also get the ability to make decisions, at zero.
我们也可以在等于0的地方 做出决策
The neurons that we'll use a lot in this course, and are probably the commonest
这门课程中我们使得很多的一种神经元 可能也是在人工神经网络中
kinds of neurons to use in artificial neuron [inaudible], are sigmoid neurons.
使用得最广泛的神经元 是S型神经元
They give a real valued output that is a smooth and bounded function of their total
这种神经元的输出它的总输入的 一个平滑而有界的函数
input. It's typical to use the logistic function,
通常使用的是逻辑函数 (logistic function)
where the total input is computed as before, as a bias plus what comes in on
总输入z 的计算方式和之前相同 即偏置量
the input lines, weighted. The output for a logistic neuron is one
加上权重和 其输出则是
over one plus e to the minus, the total input.
1 加上 e的负z次方分之一
If you think about that, if the total input's big and positive.
想一想 如果权重和是个很大的正数
E to the minus a big positive number is zero.
取反之后放到e的指数位 结果将接近0
And so, the output will be one. If the total input's big and negative, E
所以整个输出将会是1 如果权重和是个绝对值很大的负数
to the minus a big negative number is a large number, and so the output will be
那么指数项将会是个很大的正数 整个输出将会是0
zero. So the input output function looks like
所以输入输出函数看起来就像这样
this. When, the total input's zero, e to the
当总输入时0时
minus zero is one, so the output's a half. And the nice thing about a sigmoid is it
e 的0次方是1 所以输出就是0.5 S型曲线的一个优良性质是
has, smooth derivatives. The derivatives, change continuously.
它有光滑的导函数 即它的导函数是连续的
And, so they're nicely behaved, and they make it easy to do learning as we'll see
这些优良性质 让我们更容易使用它来进行学习
in lecture three. Finally the stochastic binary neurons.
正如我们将在第三讲里看到的那样 最后是随机性阈值型神经元
They use just the same equations as logistic units.
这种神经元使用与逻辑型神经元一样的方程
They compute their total input the same way and they use the logistic function to
它首先按同样的方法计算出总输入 然后用逻辑函数计算出一个实数
compute a real value which is the probability that they will output a spike.
这个实数将作为输出信号的概率
But then instead of outputting that probability as a real number they actually
它并不是直接输出这个概率
make a probabilistic decision, and so what they actually output is either a one or a
而是基于这个概率做一个选择 它的输出实际上是要么1 要么0
zero. They're intrinsically random.
从本质上来说 这个输出的随机的
So they're treating the P as the probability of producing a one, not as a
所以这种神经元将 p 作为输出为1 的概率 而不是一个实际的输出
real number. Of course, if the input is very big and
当然 如果总输入是非常大的正数
positive they will almost always produce a one.
输出将几乎总是1
If the input's big and negative they'll almost always produce a zero.
如果输入是一个绝对值很大的负数 那么输出将几乎总是0
We can do a similar trick with rectified linear units.
我们可以对分段线性神经元做类似的处理
We can say that the output, there's real value that comes out of a rectified linear
我们可以说 分段函数的输出值 那个实数值
unit, if its input is above zero, is the rate of producing spikes.
如果大于0的话 就是产生信号的速率
So that's deterministic. But once we've figured out these rate of
这是决定性的 但是如果我们把信号产生的速率
producing spikes, the actual times at which spikes are produced is a random
即信号实际上产生了多少次 看成一个随机过程
process. It's a Poisson process.
它其实就是泊松分布
So the rectified linear unit determines the rate, but intrinsic randomness in the
所以分段线性函数决定了信号产生的速率 而它内在的随机性
unit determines when the spikes are actually produced.
则决定了这些信号什么时候产生 翻译 Pan Zhimeng